Zeeshan Tanveer

I have been working as a Software Engineer since 2018, a self-motivated professional who likes to solve problems. I merge a passion successfully for usability and user experience with strong technical knowledge and SDLC to create cool Windows and macOS-based applications for direct printing from the Web applications. My repertoire includes

+92-312-0576200



in linkedin.com/in/zeeshan-tanveer

programming languages and tools such as PHP, Laravel, React.js, PHP-based Framework development and more.

SKILLS

PHP Curl HTML Bootstrap JavaScript Jquery MySql PhpStorm Laravel **API Integration** Debuging **REST APIs SOAP** Python OS (Windows, MAC) Communication with Web NodeJs React Js

Muridke, Pakistan

CPanel Analysis Swagger Documentation Teamwork

z.tanvir22@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

AlignPX Technologies

03/2019 - Present Lahore.Pakistan

Responsibilities

- Analyze the client's requirements to develop new projects and improve the existing system. Also, manage and maintain the system once it is put into production.
- Convey effectively to the project manager about all task progress, evaluations, suggestions, and schedules along with technical and process issues. Also, ensure that my team will meet the deadline of all the tasks.
- Design the architecture of a system and update it with new features. Also, recommend improvements to enhance the user experience and customer satisfaction.
- Review the pull requests and design documents to ensure the required functionalities are implemented by the team.
- Build innovative, state-of-the-art applications and collaborate with the User Experience (UX) team.
- Open-minded to new solutions, forward-thinking and strong ability to adapt Git version control workflows.

Software Engineer

Topdot Software House

08/2018 - 03/2019 Responsibilities

- Analyze clients' requirements and implement the new features in the e-commerce applications. Also, debug the issues and resolve them.
- Write migrations and perform ETL process in the web applications.
- Managing multiple projects at a time.
- Integrate the third party APIs.
- Attend daily scrum meeting.

EDUCATION

BS (Computer Science)

Virtual University of Pakistan

09/2014 - 10/2018

Intermediate in Computer Science Al-dawa model high school Muridke

CGPA 3.32 06/2011 - 06/2013

CERTIFICATIONS

Network Defense & Cyber Operations (08/2020 - 09/2021) URL: shorturl.at/tAFL6

Al For Everyone (06/2021 - 07/2021) URL: https://coursera.org/share/8c7cf6c92ecf5f330da6551b1663ded0 70%

Lahore.Pakistan

ACHIEVEMENTS

Direct/Silent Print Applications

AlignPx Technology

12/2022 - 03/2023

Achievements

- Developed .net Application for Windows OS and Objective-C Application for macOS that connect with the web application and enable the users to print different PDF or PNG files to the printer without interacting browser's print dialog window.
- Print the different files to different printers with a single click with 100% print quality and print size.
- Integrated succesfully with (freightdesk.online) web application and many merchants of e-commerce stores are using direct print applications based on their Operating System (Windows or macOS).

FreightDesk Online - Shopify Application

AlignPx Technology

11/2022 - 12/2022

Achievements

- Developed and published the application successfully on the Shopify App Store (https://apps.shopify.com/freightdesk-online-1).
- Enable the merchants of the Shopify store to automate the shipping with freight, parcel, and postal carriers.
- Virtually eliminate manual data entry in the order fulfillment process with 100% accuracy of orders details.

FreightDesk Online

AlianPx Technology

09/2019 - Present

https://freightdesk.online

Achievements

- Automate LTL freight, parcel, and postal shipping for online merchants.
- Support integrated for the WooCommerce, Shopify, BigCommerce, Magento, Prestashop, Squarespace, and WIX e-commerce platforms.
- Support integrated for the 32 LTL Freight shipping providers and 6 Parcel & Postal shipping providers.
- Quote, book, track the shipments and update the e-commerce stores with the tracking number and shipment status.

PROJECTS

Direct & Silent Printing Applications for (Windows, MacOS) (12/2022 - Present)

FreightDesk Online (09/2019 - Present)

https://freightdesk.online

Mondecheval (mondecheval.com)

https://mondecheval.com

Gardenia (gardenia.net)

https://www.gardenia.net

https://housepilot.de

HousePilot

LANGUAGES

Urdu & Hindi









English









FreightDesk Online Shopify App (11/2022 - Present)

https://apps.shopify.com/freightdesk-online-1

https://wordpress.org/plugins/search/eniture

B&B Manufacturing (bbmfg.com)

ShoppingBin (shoppingbin.com)

https://shoppingbin.com

Kotore (kotore.com)

https://kotore.com

WordPress Plugins

https://bbmfg.com



INTERESTS





Coffee

Traveling

ሕ Listen Music